<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Homepage on Michael B. Wong</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content in Homepage on Michael B. Wong</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>/sections/aboutme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/sections/aboutme/</guid><description>I am an assistant professor in management and strategy with a joint appointment in economics at HKU Business School. I received my BA from Harvard University in 2012 and my PhD from MIT in 2022.
I am an applied microeconomist. My interest includes labor economics, organizational economics, housing, and money and barter. Here is my CV. You can reach me at mbwong@hku.hk or DM me on Twitter. I am hiring a pre-doctoral research assistant.</description></item><item><title/><link>/sections/chinese/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/sections/chinese/</guid><description>加強富戶審查 劏房戶免受苦？ (明報, 2024-5-16, 與何漢樑)
香港劏房問題之出路 (香港信報, 2024-2-14)
人才得失與香港前景：領英社交資料佐證 (香港經濟政策綠皮書, 2024-1-10, 與關穎倫和鄧希煒)
利用數據和算法減低公屋輪候時間 (香港經濟政策綠皮書, 2024-1-10, 與王欣儀和黃美施)
香港房屋危機之謎 (香港經濟政策綠皮書, 2022-9-23)
預算案500億推創科 怎用得其所 (香港經濟日報, 2018-3-18)
社會面對新挑戰 須3方面調整 (香港經濟日報, 2017-9-13)</description></item><item><title/><link>/sections/personal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/sections/personal/</guid><description>Things I learned in Grad School (the Hard Way)
Tips for excelling as a PhD student
How to have productive PhD advisor meetings</description></item><item><title/><link>/sections/policy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/sections/policy/</guid><description>Hong Kong’s economic recovery hinges on having enough adequate housing (South China Morning Post, 2024-8-9)
Hong Kong must stop letting the well-off hog public rental housing (South China Morning Post, 2024-5-4, with Jimmy Ho)
Why is Hong Kong Housing So Expensive? (HKU FOSS presentation, 2024-3-6)
The Solution to Hong Kong’s Subdivided Housing Crisis (Translated from Hong Kong Economic Journal, 2024-2-14)
Brain Drain, Brain Gain, and The Future of Hong Kong: Evidence from LinkedIn Profiles (Hong Kong Economic Policy Green Paper, 2024-1-10, with Alan P.</description></item><item><title/><link>/sections/teaching/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/sections/teaching/</guid><description>Current: Instructor for HKU&amp;rsquo;s PMGM7004 (Global Management from Economics Perspectives) and PMGM7019 (Economics of Strategy and Organization).
Previous: TA for MIT&amp;rsquo;s Intro Micro (undergrad, 2022), Intermediate Micro (undergrad, 2018-20), Applied Econ for Managers (EMBA, 2019), Org Econ (PhD, 2018), and Industrial Organization II (PhD, 2022).</description></item></channel></rss>